Cranford's giving you a look.
克兰福德正在给你看。
There. Go and have a look.
Go and have a look.
那里。去看看。
去看看吧。
I don't know why. I saved a cow
of his last week.
我不知道为什么。我
上周救了他的一头牛。
Poor thing had colic.
可怜的东西有绞痛。
Sorry, ladies and gentlemen.
对不起，女士们，先生们。
It says eight o'clock on there.
那里说八点。
Quite exciting.
相当令人兴奋。
Hello! Hello.
你好！你好。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
And then a gasp of
amazement and satisfaction
然后是
惊讶和满足的喘息
runs around the world.
跑遍世界。
The Prime Minister decides to fly
to a personal meeting
总理决定飞往
个人会议
with the German Chancellor,
so after 69 years of a busy life,
和德国总理在一起，
在忙碌了69年之后，
Mr Chamberlain makes his first
trip in a plane.
张伯伦先生第一次
乘坐飞机旅行。
There's proof of his determination.
有证据证明他的决心。
The German Chancellor
德国总理
regards the situation,
看情况，
it seems to me, to be one in which
discussions between him and me
在我看来，是
他和我之间的讨论
It'll get sorted.
它会得到排序。
..may have useful consequences.
..可能会产生有用的后果。
Are your parents
still coming down to see you?
你爸妈
还来看你吗？
The day after tomorrow.
They can only stay the one night.
后天。
他们只能住一晚。
Hello.
你好。
She's dead.
她死了。
Dead?
死的？
Aye, she is. Dead.
是的，她是。死的。
Not her!
不是她！
Me cow, you silly beggar!
我牛，你这个傻乞丐！
I am sorry about that.
我很抱歉。
And I don't think it was owt to do
with her stomach, neither.
而且我不认为这
与她的胃有关，也不是。
Sorry.
对不起。
And...
和...
And here's another thing,
还有一件事，
you never sent me
that salve you promised me either.
你也从来没有把
你答应我的药膏寄给我。
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
That it's beyond saving.
那是无法挽救的。
I thought I'd
get in for your parents.
我以为我会
加入你的父母。
They're still stopping by tomorrow?
他们明天还来吗？
Is there any more mustard?
还有芥末吗？
You've got legs.
你有腿。
They're welcome to stay, you know.
欢迎他们留下来，你知道。
It's no bother making up
another bed.
再铺
一张床也不费事。
They've got the inn booked.
They didn't want to impose.
客栈已经订好了。
他们不想强加。
Has your mum got any idea you're
not coming back?
你妈妈知道你
不会回来了吗？
I didn't want to do it
over the phone.
我不想
通过电话做这件事。
With everything else going on in
the world, maybe she'll mind less.
随着
世界上其他一切都在发生，也许她会不那么介意。
What's this?
这是什么？
Oh, just...looking to the future,
哦，只是……展望未来，
making decisions.
做出决定。
I'm still thinking about it. You're
a good vet. There's only one exam.
我还在想。你是
个好兽医。只有一场考试。
I can help you revise if you like.
Aw.
如果你愿意，我可以帮你修改。
噢。
My gallant crew, good morning!
我勇敢的船员们，早上好！
An enjoyable evening with Diana?
Mind your beeswax!
与戴安娜度过一个愉快的夜晚？
注意你的蜂蜡！
Oh, God, man, you smell like
a tart's handbag!
哦，天哪，伙计，你闻起来像
馅饼的手提包！
Parma Violet, if I'm not mistaken.
帕尔马紫罗兰，如果我没记错的话。
I wondered where my bath salts
had gone!
我想知道我的浴盐
去哪儿了！
Oh, he had a rough time of it
last night. Oh, aye.
哦，他
昨晚过得很艰难。哦，是的。
I was at the cinema with Helen...
I'll get it.
我和海伦一起去看电影……
我会明白的。
..but Cranford wouldn't stop
going on about some bloody salve.
..但克兰福德不会停止
谈论一些该死的药膏。
I'll do it.
我会做的。
It would have been nice to have
one night out with Helen
和海伦出去玩一晚就好了
that didn't end in disaster.
这并没有以灾难告终。
When are you going to stop this
nonsense and get wed?
你打算什么时候停止这种
胡说八道并结婚？
Why are you laughing?
你笑什么？
You're not serious, are you?
你不是认真的吧？
But I've no money, no house.
Where would we live?
但是我没有钱，没有房子。
我们会住在哪里？
Here, of course. With Tristan
sleeping in the cupboard?
在这里，当然。特里斯坦
睡在橱柜里？
I wouldn't mind waking up
to Helen...
我不介意叫醒
海伦……
Sorry, that's inappropriate!
But it's true.
对不起，不合适！
但这是真的。
Gather ye rosebuds while ye may,
Old Time is still a-flying;
趁你可能时，收集你的玫瑰花蕾，
旧时光仍在飞翔；
And this same flower that smiles
today, tomorrow will be dying.
而这朵
今天微笑的花，明天就会凋零。
I'm not getting married!
我不结婚！
You're getting married?!
I'm not!
你要结婚了？！
我不是！
Caution - often a virtue,
but you carry it too far.
小心——通常是一种美德，
但你做得太过分了。
You need to take a chance,
lash out a little.
你需要抓住机会，
猛烈抨击一下。
Carpe some diem! Throw off these
hesitant ways
及时行乐！甩掉这些
犹豫的方式
and, remember, there is a tide
in the affairs of men
并且，请记住，人们
的事务有潮起潮落
which taken at the flood...
这是在洪水中拍摄的……
Yes, Siegfried, all right,
all right.
是的，齐格弗里德，好吧，
好吧。
Stop it. Who was on the phone?
停下来。谁在打电话？
Mrs Dalby. She wants you to look
over her stirks.
达尔比夫人。她想让你看看
她的马鞭。
Why aren't you off to school yet?
你怎么还不去上学？
I just wanted to see about the cows.
我只是想看看奶牛。
Billy Francis Dalby, if you're not
on your bike this second...
比利·弗朗西斯·达尔比，如果你现在不
骑自行车……
Mum!
妈妈！
You must be proud of him.
你一定为他感到骄傲。
Oh, I am that.
哦，我就是这样。
Now, I know you told me not to put
them out again,
现在，我知道你告诉我不要再把
它们放出来，
but we worked through the hay
so fast,
但我们干草的
速度太快了，
I couldn't afford to keep feeding
them cake.
我负担不起继续喂
他们蛋糕。
I can see they've been suffering
with diarrhoea.Yeah.
我可以看到他们一直在
腹泻。是的。
It seems to have happened
within a few days.
这似乎是
在几天内发生的。
Maybe it's something they've eaten.
也许这是他们吃过的东西。
You have any idea what it might be?
你知道它可能是什么吗？
There's a few possibilities.
有几种可能性。
The most troubling is it could
be salmonella.
最令人不安的是它可能
是沙门氏菌。
Right.
对。
Let's wait until we know before
we start worrying.
让我们等知道了再
开始担心。
I'll take some samples,
get them analysed,
我会取一些样本，
让他们分析，
and by tomorrow, we'll know what
we're dealing with.
到明天，我们就会知道
我们在处理什么。
I sometimes wonder...
我有时想知道...
..maybe we'd be better off
if I'd just listened to you
..
如果我听你的，也许我们会过得更好
and sold up whilst we still had
the chance.
在我们还有
机会的时候卖掉了。
You kept the farm for Billy,
to give him hope, a future.
你为比利保留了农场，
给他希望，一个未来。
Oh, we spent all that money
on cake as well.
哦，我们也把所有的钱都花在了
蛋糕上。
We need to wait for the results
and then we'll deal with it.
我们需要等待结果
，然后我们会处理它。
So let's stop all this talk about
moving on.
所以让我们停止所有关于
继续前进的讨论。
Your life is here.
This is where you belong.
你的生活在这里。
这是你属于的地方。
Thanks, James.
谢谢，詹姆斯。
Don't forget to
stop by the house for a brew.
不要忘记
在房子里停下来喝一杯。
Well, you see here, Mr Thomas,
好吧，你看这里，托马斯先生，
what I'm saying is
they call themselves vets,
我要说的是
他们自称是兽医，
and they're all right with cattle
and that class of thing,
他们对牛
和那种东西没问题，
but they're no use with cats
and dogs, you mark my words.
但它们对猫和狗没有用
，你记下我的话。
What you need is
some of my shampoos.
你需要的是
我的一些洗发水。
Oh, that will see him right as rain
in a minute, won't it, Rex?
哦，
一分钟后他就会像雨一样，不是吗，雷克斯？
Won't it, my sweetheart?
不会吧，亲爱的？
You're starting early.
你开始早了。
Do I detect a note of judgment
in your tone, Maggie?
我
从你的语气中是否察觉到一丝判断力，玛姬？
Far be it from me.
离我很远。
Oh, wheesht, Rex.
哦，咳咳，雷克斯。
You'll give yourself a sore throat.
你会让自己喉咙痛。
Rex!
雷克斯！
Come here, Rex!
过来，雷克斯！
Rex!
雷克斯！
He came out of nowhere!
他不知从何而来！
It's all right. I'll take care
of him.
没关系。我会照顾
他的。
What are you doing?!
你在做什么？！
Poor thing! Come on, now.
可怜的东西！来吧，现在。
Come on, now.
来吧，现在。
He needs a vet, Mrs Donovan. Rex...
他需要兽医，多诺万太太。雷克斯...
My boy!
我的孩子！
I've no doubt Mrs Donovan's
shampoos are marvellous for cleaning
我毫不怀疑多诺万夫人的
洗发水非常适合清洁
a dog's fur, but they'll do nothing
to mend a broken hip.
狗的皮毛，但他们不会
修补骨折的臀部。
If you'd like to wait, Mr Thomas,
如果你愿意等，托马斯先生，
then I'm sure Mr Farnon will be
with you in a minute.Thank you.
那么我相信法农先生马上就会
和你在一起。谢谢。
Siegfried, hit by a car. Hold on!
齐格弗里德，被车撞了。坚持，稍等！
Hold on!
坚持，稍等！
What are you going to do to him?
你要对他做什么？
Mrs Donovan, perhaps you should
wait in the living room.
多诺万太太，也许你应该
在客厅等着。
I am not leaving my dog!
我不会离开我的狗！
What happened exactly?
究竟发生了什么？
Oh, he bolted and then a car came.
哦，他狂奔，然后一辆汽车来了。
Chloroform. There's no need.
氯仿。没有必要。
Has he gone?
他走了吗？
No, he hasn't! That's my dog!
不，他没有！那是我的狗！
Massive internal haemorrhaging,
I think.
我认为是大量内出血。
I can feel damage
to the pelvic bone.
我能感觉到
骨盆的损伤。
Nothing we could have done.
我们什么也做不了。
I'm so sorry, Mrs Donovan.
我很抱歉，多诺万夫人。
Hi, James. How are you doing, Jenny?
嗨，詹姆斯。你好吗，珍妮？
Hello. Hello.
你好。你好。
What is it?
它是什么？
Oh, nothing. There was just
some pollen in the air.
哦，没什么。
空气中只有一些花粉。
That's it, Candy. Good girl.
就是这样，糖果。好姑娘。
Jenny, you're not jinking off
school, are you?
珍妮，你不会放学
吧？
I said she could. She don't want
to miss the birth.
我说她可以。她不想
错过出生。
It's all Pythagoras and his blooming
triangles anyway.
无论如何，这都是毕达哥拉斯和他盛开的三角形。
How's that supposed to help me
milk the cows?
那怎么能帮我
挤奶呢？
Speaking of which,
you might make yourself useful.
说到这里，
你可能会让自己变得有用。
I'll leave you pair to it.
我会让你配对的。
I was always trying
to skip school at her age.Really?
在她这个年纪，我总是想逃学。真的吗？
I always had you down as a bit
of a goody-two-shoes.
我总是让你失望，因为你有点像
双鞋。
I'll try not to take
offence at that.
我会尽量不
冒犯。
Shall we have a look at you, then,
Candy, to see how your foal's doing?
那么，我们要
不要看看你，Candy，看看你的小马驹怎么样了？
Many more calls today?
今天还有很多电话吗？
You're my last. I've got to get
a sample from the Dalbys
你是我的最后一个 我必须
从 Dalbys那里得到一个样品
over to Harrogate.
It could be salmonella.
到哈罗盖特。
可能是沙门氏菌。
Oh, that's the last thing
Phyllis needs.
哦，这是
菲利斯最不需要的东西。
When will you get the results?
你什么时候会得到结果？
Should be a day. It's a fair drive.
应该是一天。这是一个公平的驱动器。
If you're able to get away, it'd be
nice to have some company.
如果你能逃脱，
有一些陪伴就好了。
There's a few things I need to
finish on the farm first.
我需要先
在农场完成几件事。
I'm happy to wait.
我很高兴等待。
I thought we could have dinner
with my folks tomorrow.
我想我们
明天可以和我的家人共进晚餐。
Together? All of us?
一起？我们所有人？
Well, I'd like to introduce you to
them since you are...
好吧，我想把你介绍给
他们，因为你是……
Well, we are...you know.
嗯，我们是……你知道。
And I met your dad.
I even wore his shoes.Right.
我遇见了你爸爸。
我什至穿了他的鞋子。对。
I must check I've got a clean
frock, then.
那么我必须检查一下我有没有一件干净的
连衣裙。
Do you think he suffered at all?
你觉得他受苦了吗？
I'm certain he didn't.
我确定他没有。
You can leave him here
if you'd prefer.
如果你愿意，你可以把他留在这里。
Oh, no. My Rex will have
a proper burial.
不好了。我的雷克斯将有
一个适当的埋葬。
There's a spot down
by my boat...
我的船旁边有一个地方...
.. under a tree.
He used to like it.
.. 在树下。
他曾经喜欢它。
Sounds perfect.
听起来很完美。
Shall I carry him over for you?
要我替你背他吗？
Aye, well...
嗯，嗯...
I suppose that's all right, then.
我想那没问题。
Did you have him long?
你养他很久了吗？
Eight years all in. He must have
seen a lot of the world with you.
八年了。他一定
和你一起看过很多世界。
I'm sure he had a wonderful life.
我相信他过着美好的生活。
What would you know about our life?
你对我们的生活有什么了解？
No, no, I'm not saying I do,
I just imagine.
不，不，我不是说我知道，
我只是想象。
Whenever I saw him out and about
with you, he always looked happy.
每当我看到他和
你一起出去走走时，他总是看起来很开心。
You know where you are with a dog.
They're loyal.
你知道你和狗在一起的地方。
他们很忠诚。
They don't judge you for who or what
you are.
他们不会根据你是谁或
你是什么来判断你。
What is it you're after?
你在追求什么？
Cos I'm telling you, if it's
money, you'll get none for me.
因为我告诉你，如果是
钱，你就拿不到我。
I'm not after anything.
我不追求任何东西。
Right. Well, why are you
doing this, then?
对。那么，你为什么
要这样做呢？
Sure, you hardly know me.
当然，你几乎不认识我。
I saw what happened to your dog
and I wanted to help him.
我看到你的狗发生了什么事
，我想帮助他。
And I suppose, deep down, it also
means I wanted to help you too.
我想，在内心深处，这也
意味着我也想帮助你。
It's not just the animals.
不仅仅是动物。
Are you soft in the head?
你的脑袋软吗？
What are you on about?
你在说什么？
It doesn't matter.
Something somebody said to me once.
没关系。
曾经有人对我说过的话。
More than once.
不止一次。
You're a funny man.
Did anyone ever tell you that?
你是个有趣的人。
有没有人告诉过你？
More often than I care to mention.
比我更愿意提及的次数。
Well, you might take it
as a compliment.
好吧，你可以把它
当作一种恭维。
There's room enough in this world
这个世界有足够的空间
for folks of all
kinds of different stripes.
对于
各种不同条纹的人。
Who's that fella?
那家伙是谁？
You're all right, he's with me.
你没事，他在我身边。
That's my boat.
那是我的船。
And my lamb there.
还有我的羔羊。
My Rex is dead.
我的雷克斯死了。
He felt nothing.
他没什么感觉。
You wains can help me
lay him to rest.
你可以帮我
让他安息。
How old were your parents
when they got married?
你父母几岁
结婚？
Dad said he were barely out of short
trousers when he asked me mam.
爸爸
问我妈妈时说他几乎没有穿短裤。
I don't know my parents got engaged.
Never thought to ask.
我不知道我父母订婚了。
没想过问。
No. You never struck me
as the romantic type.
不，你从来没有让我觉得
浪漫的类型。
I am romantic!
我很浪漫！
Oh, no, I didn't mean it
in a bad way.
哦，不，我不是故意的
。
I just meant you're not one
for grand gestures
我只是想说你不是
那种大手笔的人
or anything too extravagant.
或任何过于奢侈的东西。
I like that about you.
我喜欢你这一点。
My mum thinks if I stay in this job,
I'll never find a wife.
我妈妈认为如果我继续做这份工作，
我将永远找不到妻子。
And Siegfried thinks
I should just get on and marry you!
齐格弗里德认为
我应该继续和你结婚！
Oh! What did you say?
哦！你说什么？
I laughed.
我笑了。
He said I'd a habit of being
too cautious,
他说我习惯了
过于谨慎，
that I don't have the courage
of my convictions
我没有
坚定信念的勇气
and see dangers
where there are none.
并
在没有危险的地方看到危险。
That's how Siegfried put it anyway.
反正齐格弗里德就是这么说的。
You know, there's
something in what Siegfried said.
你知道，
齐格弗里德说的有些道理。
In what way?
以什么方式？
Well, you do sometimes overthink,
see catastrophe round every corner.
好吧，您有时确实想多了，
每个角落都会看到灾难。
It's not something I want to do.
这不是我想做的事情。
Then don't. Don't?
那就别了。别？
Overthink. Worry less.
想多了。少担心。
I wish I could.Well, you can.
I can?
我希望我可以。好吧，你可以。
我可以？
Why not?
为什么不？
Just decide to be
positive and take the plunge?
只是决定
积极并冒险？
What's the worst that could happen?
可能发生的最坏情况是什么？
You'd say no!To what?
你会说不！什么？
Asking you to marry me.
求你嫁给我。
Stop the car.
停车。
Helen, I'm fine with you
not being ready.
海伦，你
还没准备好，我很好。
I just...
我只是...
I just need a moment.
我只需要一点时间。
But I'm not afraid to say it.
但我不怕说出来。
Say what?
说什么？
I want to spend
the rest of my life with you.
我想
和你共度余生。
Here in the Dales.
在山谷这里。
I'm not afraid either.
我也不害怕。
You're not?
你不？
No.
不。
James, why do you smell like that?
詹姆斯，你为什么有那种味道？
I ran out of bath salts so I used
Mrs Hall's.
我的浴盐用完了，所以我用了
霍尔夫人的。
I may have overdone it somewhat.
我可能有点过头了。
What? Is it the smell? Don't worry,
it'll be gone in a couple of days.
什么？是气味吗？别着急，
过几天就好了。
It's not the smell. The ring?
这不是气味。戒指？
I haven't got a ring! You see, this
is the problem with not planning!
我没有戒指！你看，这
就是没有计划的问题！
It's Dad. I take it you haven't
spoke to him?
是爸爸。我想你没有
和他说过话？
Look Dad in the eye.
看着爸爸的眼睛。
And don't gabble. Sometimes
when you're nervous, you gabble.
并且不要胡言乱语。有时候，
当你紧张的时候，你就会胡言乱语。
What do you mean, I gabble?
I don't gabble. When have I ever...
你什么意思，我胡说八道？
我不胡说八道。我什么时候...
I hardly ever.
Unless I'm really nervous maybe.
我很少。
除非我真的很紧张。
Right.
对。
Something's wrong.
出问题了。
I would have sent for Mr Farnon.
我会派人去请法农先生的。
There's summat up with our
Candy. Come quick, will you?
我们的
糖果有总结。快点来好吗？
The uterus is twisted.
子宫是扭曲的。
And that's bad, is it?
这很糟糕，是吗？
Give me a hand.
帮帮我。
Now, when it's open like this, you
can put your hand straight through.
现在，当它像这样打开时，你
可以直接把手伸进去。
But if I twist it...
Nothing can get through.
但如果我扭曲它......
没有什么可以通过的。
That's what's
happening inside Candy.
这就是
糖果内部发生的事情。
And we need to unwind it.
If you can't?
我们需要放松它。
如果你不能？
We'll lose them both, love.
我们会失去他们两个，亲爱的。
Jenny, go up to the phone box
and call Skeldale House.
珍妮，走到电话亭前
，给 Skeldale House 打电话。
We're going to need some help.
我们需要一些帮助。
Oh.
哦。
Darrowby 2-2-9-7.
达罗比 2-2-9-7。
Oh, Jenny, hello, how are you?
哦，珍妮，你好，你好吗？
Mr Farnon?
法农先生？
He's just coming, love.
他刚来，亲爱的。
Jenny Alderson.
珍妮奥尔德森。
Jenny?
珍妮？
I'll be out there straight away.
我马上就出来。
I'll get your jacket.
我去拿你的夹克。
Is something going on?
有什么事吗？
Problem with the Aldersons' horse.
James needs my help.
奥尔德森家的马有问题。
詹姆斯需要我的帮助。
Hold that.
拿着那个。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
This morning,
I had another talk
今天早上，
我又谈了一次
with the German Chancellor,
Herr Hitler.
与德国总理
希特勒在一起。
Here is the paper...
这是纸...
Hello, you.
你好，你。
..which bears his name upon it
as well as mine.
..上面写着他
和我的名字。
Good book?
好书？
Mm.
毫米。
Some of you perhaps have already
heard what it contains...
你们中的一些人可能已经
听说过它包含的内容......
..but I would just like to read it
to you.
..但我只想读
给你听。
..the British Minister have had
a further meeting today...
..英国大臣
今天有进一步的会议......
Siegfried! Wait!
齐格弗里德！等待！
..and are agreed in recognising
..并同意承认
that the question of Anglo-German
relations is of the first importance
英德
关系问题是最重要的
for the two countries
and for Europe.
为两国
和欧洲。
We regard the agreement
signed last night
我们认为
昨晚签署的协议
and at the Anglo-German Naval
Agreement as symbolic of the desire
并在英德海军
协定中作为愿望的象征
of our two peoples never to
go to war with one another again.
我们两国人民永远不会
再次发生战争。
Good evening, Richard, Helen, Jenny.
What's the presentation?
晚上好，理查德，海伦，珍妮。
介绍是什么？
Uterus is still twisted.
子宫仍然扭曲。
It's too late to carry out
a caesarean.
剖腹产已经太晚了。
Don't worry, the cavalry's here.
别担心，骑兵来了。
So you're going to try to turn
her over to unwind it?
所以你打算试着把
她翻过来放松一下？
That's the plan. I'll take hold of
the hooves.
这就是计划。我会抓住
蹄子。
Siegfried, Mr Alderson, when I
say, roll the horse over.
齐格弗里德，奥尔德森先生，当我
说的时候，把马翻过来。
Hopefully it'll untwist
the uterus around the foal.
希望它能解开
小马驹周围的子宫。
Tris, give them a hand
if they need it.
Tris，
如果他们需要帮助他们。
Jenny, love... I'm staying. Ready?
珍妮，亲爱的……我要留下来。准备好？
Come on, then.
那就来吧。
It's all right. Candy was their
mother's horse.
没关系。糖果是他们
母亲的马。
It'll put everything right.
它会把一切都做好。
I've got hold of the feet.
我已经抓住了脚。
All right. Now, roll her.
好的。现在，滚她。
Stop, stop, hold on.
停下，停下，坚持。
I'm losing grip
of the foal's hooves.
我失去
了对小马驹蹄子的抓地力。
All right.
好的。
I've got them. Ready?
我有他们。准备好？
Go.
走。
Is it working?
它有效吗？
Yeah, I can feel it loosening.
是的，我能感觉到它在松动。
It's coming towards me.
它向我走来。
The foal's coming.
小马驹来了
It's coming. It's coming!
它来了。它来了！
It's coming.
它来了。
He's done it! It's out!
他做到了！出来了！
Oh. Evening.
哦。晚上。
Thought we'd drop by and see
if you fancied a stroll?
以为我们会
顺便过来看看你是否喜欢散步？
Let me grab my coat. Come here.
让我抓住我的外套。过来。
Go one.Aw!
去一个。啊！
Go on.Go on. Aw!
继续，继续。啊！
One more, one more.
Come on, little one.
再来一张，再来一张。
来吧，小家伙。
Go on, little one.
加油，小家伙。
Yay! There we are.
好极了！我们到了。
Our work here is done.
我们这里的工作已经完成。
I'll call her Joan. After mum.
我会叫她琼。妈妈之后。
Aye, that'll do.
是的，就可以了。
We'll, um, leave 'em be.
我们会，嗯，离开他们。
Mother knows what's best for 'em.
妈妈知道什么对他们最好。
Jenny...
珍妮...
Jenny. But...
珍妮。但...
Must be going bloomin' soft.
一定要绽放'软。
She's, er...
She's a good girl, is Candy.
她是个好女孩，是坎迪。
Mr Alderson...
奥尔德森先生...
..I'd like to marry your daughter.
..我想娶你的女儿。
Right.
对。
You better come up to t'house, lad.
你最好到你家来，小伙子。
It's been good weather for t'hay.
Aye, it is. That's true.
t'hay 的天气很好。
是的，它是。确实如此。
Drop of rain won't do any ill, mind.
Oh, definitely.
一滴雨不会有什么坏处，介意。
哦，一定。
Definitely, just to...moisten it.
当然，只是为了……润湿它。
No, I'm fine.
不我没事。
Actually... Thank you.
其实……谢谢。
I had a wife in a thousand.
我有一千个妻子。
I've heard a lot about her.
She certainly sounds it.
我听说过很多关于她的事。
她当然听起来。
Nobody thought she'd settle for
a fella like me. You know?
没有人认为她会接受
像我这样的人。你懂？
But she did.
但她做到了。
One in a thousand, she were.
千分之一，她是。
Bit bloody stubborn, though,
虽然有点顽固，
she set her mind to it.
她下定决心。
I... All right, why not?
我……好吧，为什么不呢？
You know, I can't...
你知道，我不能...
I can't picture her face
the way that I used to.
我无法像以前那样想象她的脸
。
Time passes.
时间流逝。
But I see it in them girls of mine,
I see it in our Jenny.
但我在我的女孩身上看到了，
我在我们的珍妮身上看到了。
She has that look when
she gets cross, and
当
她生气时，她有那种表情，而且
our Helen has her smile.
我们的海伦有她的微笑。
I see it sometimes when I catch her
looking at you.
当我发现她
在看你时，我有时会看到它。
Aye.
是的。
Mr Alderson, I love Helen.
奥尔德森先生，我爱海伦。
I'll take care of her.I doubt that.
我会照顾她的。我对此表示怀疑。
She'll be t'one taking care of you,
lad. With your permission.
她不会照顾你的，
小伙子。在你的许可之下。
What for?
做什么的？
You've already asked her,
haven't you?
你已经问过她了，
不是吗？
I did. I have.
我做到了。我有。
How did you know?I told you.
你怎么知道的？我告诉过你。
That smile, her mother's smile.
那笑容，是她妈妈的笑容。
Listen.
听。
There's no point asking me
for my permission, lad.
没有必要征求我
的同意，小伙子。
That lass does exactly
as she chooses.
那个姑娘完全
按照她的选择去做。
Like her mother. Stubborn.
就像她妈妈一样。顽固。
That were Helen's mother's.
那是海伦的母亲。
My Joan.
我的琼
Might you use it?
你能用吗？
I'd be honoured.
我会很荣幸。
Thank you.Aye.
谢谢。嗯。
Good lad.
好孩子。
Leftover stool samples. Unlike
James not to have cleaned them out.
剩余的粪便样本。不像
詹姆斯没有把它们清理干净。
Lovely. Where is he, by the way?
Shouldn't he be up by now?
迷人的。顺便问一下，他在哪儿？
他现在不是应该起来了吗？
Didn't get back from the Aldersons
until late last night.
直到昨晚深夜才从奥尔德森家回来。
I know you want the salve,
Mr Cranford.
我知道你想要药膏，
克兰福德先生。
But we are not a delivery service.
但我们不是送货服务。
If you'd like to come by...
如果你愿意过来...
Get that bloody salve
sent over!
把那该死的药膏
送过来！
Rude man! Cranford?
粗鲁的人！克兰福德？
Need you ask?
你需要问吗？
I'll drop the salve round
for him later.
稍后我会
为他放下药膏。
Oh, there you are James. What time
do you call this? Sorry, Siegfried.
哦，你是詹姆斯。你这叫什么时间
？对不起，齐格弗里德。
Late night. I got waylaid at the
Aldersons.Ha-ha, really?
深夜。我在
奥尔德森被拦路了。哈哈，真的吗？
Talking to Richard.
Oh, Richard now, is it?
和理查德谈话。
哦，理查德，是吗？
Asking his permission
to marry Helen!
请求他同意
嫁给海伦！
Oh, my goodness! Congratulations!
哦，我的天啊！恭喜！
Let me give you a kiss.
让我给你一个吻。
Well, hang on,
she hasn't said yes yet.
好吧，等一下，
她还没有答应。
She has! James, well done!
她有！詹姆斯，干得好！
I got the order of things
a little muddled up.
我把事情的顺序
搞得有点混乱。
I've got you to thank for that,
Siegfried.
我要感谢你，
齐格弗里德。
Yes, well, you took your time
about it. Mr Farnon. What?
是的，好吧，你花了很多时间
。法农先生。什么？
Oh, all right. Well done.
Yes, very good, very moving.
哦那好吧。做得好。
是的，很好，很感动。
Drinks later to celebrate?
晚点喝酒庆祝？
Let's see how dinner with my parents
goes first.Are you bringing Helen?
让我们先看看我和父母的晚餐怎么
样。你带海伦来吗？
Oh, they're going to be so pleased.
哦，他们会很高兴的。
Another busy day?
又是忙碌的一天？
A list far too long and varied to
encapsulate in a few brief words.
一个列表太长而且变化多端，无法
用几个简短的词来概括。
He said he had to come to it
himself. Oh, rubbish.
他说他必须
自己来。哦，垃圾。
What happened to doing as you're
damn well told?
像你说
的那样做是怎么回事？
Go on. You better be off to meet
your parents.
继续。你最好去见
你的父母。
Hold on. I had a phone call
from a lab in Harrogate.
坚持，稍等。我接到了
来自哈罗盖特实验室的电话。
They said they didn't find anything.
他们说他们没有找到任何东西。
Why are you smiling?
Is that a good thing? Aye. It is.
你为什么笑？
那是件好事儿吗？是的。这是。
There you are.
你在这。
Come on, then.
那就来吧。
What's this?
这是什么？
Come on.
来吧。
Good boy.
好孩子。
Good boy!
好孩子！
Come on, then, you.
来吧，你。
Come on. That's it.
来吧。就是这样。
Good boy!
好孩子！
There's my boy!
有我的男孩！
Give your ma a kiss.
给你妈妈一个吻。
Let me take that for you, Dad.
Thank you, son.
爸爸，让我替你拿走。
谢谢你，儿子。
We'll drop your things at the inn,
and then we'll go for a drive.
我们会把你的东西放在客栈，
然后我们会去兜风。
Where to? You'll see.
去哪儿？你会看到的。
On a beautiful day like this,
you can see for 20 miles.
在这样美好的一天，
您可以看到 20 英里。
But when the weather comes in,
it's a brutal place.
但是当天气来临时，
这是一个残酷的地方。
Snow ten foot deep, fog so thick
you can barely see your hand
雪十英尺深，雾太浓，
几乎看不到你的手
in front of your face.
I don't like the thought of you
在你的面前。
我不喜欢你的想法
going out in weather like that.
Thank goodness you won't have to do
在这样的天气出去。
谢天谢地，你不必这样做
this much longer. It's not so bad.
这要长得多。也不是那么坏。
Slipping off in the dead of night?
在深夜滑倒？
Not coming home until morning?
早上不回家？
You'll never find a wife carrying on
like that, you know. It's unnatural.
你永远找不到这样的妻子
，你知道。这是不自然的。
And those grandkiddies don't make
themselves, you know.
你知道，那些孙子孙女不会自己做自己。
Good to see you, Dad.
很高兴见到你，爸爸。
Pick the leaves like these, and
don't be pulling up the meadowsweet,
像这样摘树叶，
不要拔掉绣线菊，
cos it needs leaf to bloom.
因为它需要叶子才能开花。
Right. Look miserable.
对。看着好惨
Hello, Mrs Donovan.
你好，多诺万夫人。
What's up with this one, then?
那这到底是怎么回事？
He's a stray.
他是个流浪汉。
Where are you taking him?
你带他去哪儿？
Well, with no home to go to,
there's really only one option.
好吧，没有家可去，
真的只有一种选择。
We'll have to put him down.
Got no-one to take care of him.
我们得把他放下来。
没人照顾他。
No-one's going to want a dog
in this state. Give him to me.
在这种状态下，没有人会想要一只狗。把他给我。
I'll have him.
我要他。
Really, he should be
checked over by a qualified vet.
真的，他应该
由合格的兽医检查。
Oh, I'll take care of him,
never you worry.
哦，我会照顾他的，
你不用担心。
He might benefit from those
shampoos of yours.
他可能会受益于
你的那些洗发水。
Maybe he's not as daft as he looks.
也许他并不像他看起来那么愚蠢。
Come on, down you get.
来吧，下来你得到。
That's it.
就是这样。
Why on earth have
you brought us here?
你到底为什么把我们带到这里来？
I've got a few jobs to get through
this afternoon.
今天下午我有几份工作要处理。
I'm sorry. It won't take long.
抱歉。不会花很长时间。
All right there, Jim?
Afternoon, Phyllis.
好吗，吉姆？
下午，菲利斯。
These are my parents,
Hannah and James.Hello.
这是我的父母，
汉娜和詹姆斯。你好。
Afternoon. Hello.
下午。你好。
What we saying then, Jim?
Don't keep us waiting.
那我们说什么，吉姆？
不要让我们等待。
Thankfully, it's not salmonella.
谢天谢地，这不是沙门氏菌。
In fact, the laboratory couldn't
find anything wrong with them.Oh.
其实实验室也
查不出他们有什么问题哦。
There must be a mistake,
because I can see how bad they are,
一定有错误，
因为我可以看到他们有多糟糕，
and they're getting worse
by the day.
他们
一天比一天更糟。
There's something
I want to show you.
有件事
我想给你看。
Come on.
Why don't we take a look?
来吧。
我们为什么不看看？
Come on! Oh...
来吧！哦...
Oh!
哦！
See this light colouration
around the eyes?
看到
眼睛周围的这种浅色了吗？
It's like they've got spectacles.
就像他们戴着眼镜一样。
Aye, that's right, Billy.
Well spotted.
是的，没错，比利。
好眼力。
I noticed it last time I was here,
but I wanted to rule out
我上次来的时候注意到了，
但我想排除
everything else to confirm
the diagnosis.
其他一切以确认
诊断。
So, what is it?
那么，它是什么？
They're suffering
from copper deficiency.
他们患有
铜缺乏症。
You can tell by the loss
of pigment in the coat -
你可以通过
皮毛中色素的损失来判断——
particularly around the eyes.
尤其是眼睛周围。
I take it by the smug look
on your face you know how to fix it.
我看
你脸上沾沾自喜的样子，你知道如何解决它。
Certainly, I do.
A simple solution given orally.
当然，我愿意。
一个简单的口头解决方案。
It'll have to be repeated, to make
sure they don't get deficient again.
它必须重复，以
确保它们不会再次出现缺陷。
Other than that,
they'll have a long and happy life.
除此之外，
他们将拥有漫长而幸福的生活。
And it is very expensive?
而且很贵？
Cheap as chips.
便宜如筹码。
Yes!
是的！
We mix it,
and you administer it yourself.
我们混合使用，
您自己管理。
I'll have some ready for you to
pick up tomorrow.
我准备了一些让你
明天去取。
Good God, Jim, don't do that to me.
天哪，吉姆，别这样对我。
I thought for a minute there
we were beaten.
我想了一会儿，
我们被打败了。
I don't think you'd ever be that,
Phyllis.
我认为你永远不会成为那个人，
菲利斯。
Well, better get back. Mm-hm.
嗯，最好回来。嗯嗯。
Get tea ready for the brood. Yeah.
Thanks, James.
为育雏准备茶。是的。
谢谢，詹姆斯。
Cheerio. Nice to meet you.
啦啦队。很高兴见到你。
See? Told you everything would be
all right. Yes, we made it.
看？告诉你一切都会
好的。是的，我们做到了。
It's beautiful up here, isn't it?
这里很美，不是吗？
Aye, it is.
是的，它是。
I'll drop you at the end
to freshen up.
我会在最后放下你
来梳洗一下。
Where are you gallivanting
off to now?
你
现在要去哪里？
I'm bringing someone to dinner
I'd like you to meet.
我要请人吃饭，
我想让你见见。
I want to say...
我想说...
..that the settlement of the
Czechoslovakian problem...
..
捷克斯洛伐克问题的解决......
..which has now been achieved...
..现在已经实现了......
..is in my view only the prelude...
..在我看来只是前奏...
..to a larger settlement...
..到一个更大的定居点......
in which all Europe may find peace.
整个欧洲都可以在其中找到和平。
Careful, you'll get messed up.
小心，你会搞砸的。
James' parents have us down as a
right bunch of scruff-backs.
詹姆斯的父母把我们当成
一群无赖。
Yeah, well, they need taking in.
是的，他们需要接受。
Otherwise they'll be roosting
all over the place.
否则它们就会
到处乱窜。
Give him here. Give him here!
给他这里。把他交给这里！
Ready to go?
准备好出发？
Erm, I'm just going to see if Deb
needs help with anything first.
嗯，我只是先看看黛布是否
需要帮助。
Don't worry.
别担心。
They're going to love you.Hm...
他们会爱你的。嗯...
Is that...? Looks like something
on the back of your dress.
就是它...？看起来像
你衣服背面的东西。
You said I couldn't do
romantic gestures.
你说我不能做
浪漫的手势。
Get up, you daft beggar.
起来，你这个愚蠢的乞丐。
Is that...?
就是它...？
Is that me mum's?
那是我妈妈的吗？
It is.
这是。
James will be back soon.
詹姆斯很快就会回来。
Drink, anyone? Whisky perhaps?
喝，有人吗？也许是威士忌？
God, yes!
天啊，是的！
We won't actually.
We're not big drinkers.
我们实际上不会。
我们不是大酒鬼。
No, neither are we.
不，我们也不是。
Special occasions.
特殊场合。
It's a fine place you have here,
Mr Farnon.
法农先生，这里真是个好地方。
James can't speak highly
enough about it.
詹姆斯对此怎么评价都
不够高。
Ah.
啊。
You must be sorry to be losing him.
你一定为失去他感到遗憾。
What?
什么？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Oh, no, me and my big mouth.
哦，不，我和我的大嘴。
Did you not know?
你不知道吗？
Hello!
你好！
Sorry that took a while.
No trouble at all, son.
抱歉，花了一段时间。
一点都不麻烦，儿子。
Mr Farnon's been keeping us
entertained.
法农先生一直让我们开心
。
We were just talking about how sorry
he'll be to see you gone.
我们只是在谈论
他会多么遗憾看到你离开。
Yes, something of a shock.
是的，有些震惊。
No doubt we'll find a replacement
easily enough.
毫无疑问，我们会
很容易找到替代品。
Siegfried.
齐格弗里德。
Who's this? Aren't you going
to introduce us?
这是谁？不
给我们介绍一下吗？
Erm, right.
嗯，对。
Mum, Dad, this is Helen...
妈妈，爸爸，这是海伦……
..my fiancee.
..我的未婚妻。
Hello. How do you do?
你好。你好吗？
It's lovely to meet you both.
很高兴认识你们俩。
Tristan, would you like to come and
set the table for dinner?
特里斯坦，你愿意过来
摆桌吃饭吗？
Why don't I give you a hand?
我为什么不帮你？
Once you're married,
结婚后，
we'll see if we can't squeeze a
bigger bed into James' room.
我们会看看能否
在詹姆斯的房间里塞一张更大的床。
Oh, should be able to manage that.
哦，应该可以管理。
It'll be a busy house,
这将是一个忙碌的房子，
but I'm sure we'll all
rub along just fine.
但我相信我们都会
相处得很好。
Mum, I want you to know this hasn't
been easy, but...
妈妈，我想让你知道这并不
容易，但是......
What?
什么？
What hasn't been easy?
什么不容易？
I should've told you sooner,
我应该早点告诉你的
but the truth is I didn't fully
know for a long time.
但事实是我
很长一段时间都不完全知道。
I'm staying here,
我留在这里，
and it's not only because of Helen.
这不仅仅是因为海伦。
What about the job?
工作呢？
I was tempted, I won't lie.
我被诱惑了，我不会撒谎。
But thinking about it's made me
realise all the more
但想想这让我
更加意识到
how much I love it here.
我是多么喜欢这里。
Every day is different.
每一天都不一样。
I wake up and I have no
idea where the job will take me.
我醒来，我不
知道这份工作会把我带到哪里。
I could be up in the High Dales
wrestling cattle
我可以在高谷
摔跤牛
or helping a dog that's had its
paw caught in a trap.
或者帮助一只
爪子陷入陷阱的狗。
It's this place, those hills...
就是这个地方，那些山……
James is too modest to ever
say this himself,
詹姆斯太谦虚了，
他自己从来不这么说，
but he's made such a difference to
so, so many people since he arrived.
但
自从他到达以来，他对这么多人产生了如此大的影响。
It's especially true for me
and my family,
对我
和我的家人来说尤其如此，
and so many others.
还有很多其他人。
That farm you visited today,
the Dalbys,
你今天参观的那个农场，
达尔比一家，
that's the second time
he's saved their herd this year.
这是
他今年第二次拯救他们的牛群。
What he does here really matters.
他在这里做什么真的很重要。
Oh, but Bill's place...
哦，但是比尔的地方...
You can work normal hours,
it's so modern and new.
您可以在正常时间工作，
它是如此现代和新颖。
That's not what makes a practice.
这不是练习的原因。
It's the people.
是人民。
I love this place.
我喜欢这个地方。
It's my home now.
现在是我的家。
You should be so proud of him.
你应该为他感到骄傲。
I certainly am.
我当然是。
And I love him
我爱他
with all my heart.
一心一意。
So long as you're both happy.
只要你们俩开心就好。
That's all we've ever wanted
for you.
这就是我们一直想要
的。
Aye, it's true.
是的，这是真的。
I wish we could convince you to
stay another night.
我希望我们能说服你
再住一晚。
No, we need to get back
and see about gaining some work.
不，我们需要回去
看看是否能获得一些工作。
I'll be back up to visit you
as soon as I can.
我会尽快回来拜访你
。
Christmas maybe.
圣诞节吧。
Visit?
访问？
You don't visit your home.
你不去你家。
It's your real home,
才是你真正的家
and it always will be.
它永远是。
I know, Mum. I didn't mean that.
我知道，妈妈。我不是那个意思。
You're my boy.
你是我的男孩
Bye, son.
再见，儿子。
You've made a nice little
life for yourself down here.
你在
这里为自己创造了美好的小生活。
Thanks, Dad.
感谢爸爸。
Look after him for us.
替我们照顾他。
I will.
我会。
Bye. Bye, love.
再见。再见了，我的爱。
Right, let's get you in that bus.
好的，让我们送你上那辆巴士。
I love you.
我爱你。
I love you, too.
我也爱你。
Oi! There you are!
哎呀！你在这！
Hey, I'll have a word with you!
嘿，我跟你说句话！
It's about that...
是关于那个...
..that damn...
……该死的……
..salve you sent me!
..salve 你寄给我的！
To peace! To Mr Chamberlain!
为了和平！张伯伦先生！
Mr Chamberlain!Good man.
张伯伦先生！好人。
Isn't it something?
不是东西吗？
You don't realise how much something
weighs on you till it's gone.
直到它消失，你才意识到有多少东西压在你身上。
I know exactly what you mean.
我确切地知道你的意思。
Now, look here, I think
it grossly unfair of you to
现在，看这里，我认为
你太不公平了
characterise my support as something
akin to the trials of Atlas.
将我的支持描述为
类似于 Atlas 的试验。
I only push you because I know you
could achieve
我只是推你，因为我知道你
可以做到
so much more than you do,
and if I didn't push you,
比你做的要多得多
如果我没有逼你
then you damn well wouldn't do
anything useful...
那么你他妈的不会做
任何有用的事情......
Here! Here he is!
这里！他在这里！
What do you think
of this one, then?
那你觉得
这个怎么样？
I cleaned the foots,
我洗了脚，
and all it took
was some of my shampoos.
只需要
我的一些洗发水。
I named him Roy.
我给他起名叫罗伊。
And to think you were going to do
away with him.
并认为你要
除掉他。
You were right, Mrs Donovan.
你说得对，多诺万夫人。
Your shampoos really seem to
have done the trick.
你的洗发水似乎真的
成功了。
Come here, you.
过来，你。
You needn't think I don't know what
you were up to.
你不必认为我不知道
你在做什么。
Come on, Roy. Come on, son.
来吧，罗伊。来吧，儿子。
How is everything?
一切还好吧？
Can I get you anything else?
我还能给你什么吗？
Any more drinks?
还有酒吗？
There was a stray
moping about the place.
这个地方有一种漫无目的的闷闷不乐。
I wanted to see
if I could do something for him
我想看看
我能不能为他做点什么
and help Mrs Donovan
at the same time.
同时帮助多诺万夫人
。
That sounds very kind of you.
听起来你真好。
Sorry, Siegfried,
you were saying something about me
对不起，齐格弗里德，
你说我的事
never doing anything useful.
从不做任何有用的事情。
I take it back.
我把它收回。
Now you're going to have
to give me some money.
现在你必须
给我一些钱。
Oh, I just bought you a drink. Don't
tell me you've guzzled it already.
哦，我刚给你买了一杯酒。别
告诉我你已经吃饱了。
So I can go back to college.
I've decided to re-sit parasitology.
所以我可以回到大学。
我决定重新参加寄生虫学。
I think veterinary practice might
be my calling after all.
我认为兽医可能
毕竟是我的职业。
Tristan, is it possible that you
got Cranford's salve
特里斯坦，你
有没有可能得到克兰福德的药膏
mixed up with a stool sample?
与粪便样本混在一起？
Just bumped into him
outside the Vulcan Inn.
刚好
在火神客栈外面撞到了他。
Said he started to rub
it in before he realised.
说他
在意识到之前就开始摩擦它。
No-one gets to be rude to Mrs H.
没有人会对 H 夫人无礼。
Quite right, well played.
说得对，打得不错。
Good boy.
好孩子。
Siegfried, I know I should've told
you about the job sooner,
齐格弗里德，我知道我应该
早点告诉你这份工作的事，
but I meant what I said.
I've learnt so much from you.
但我是认真的。
我从你那里学到了很多。
Yes, well, I couldn't help noticing
that both of you took rather a long
是的，我不禁注意到
你们俩花了很长时间
time fully to appreciate...
时间充分欣赏...
Oh, be quiet.
哦，安静。
Hear, you pair...
听说，你们配对...
..to your engagement
..你的订婚
and a very happy future together.
和一个非常幸福的未来。
Hear.
听到。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Cheers!
干杯!
So, Helen,
所以，海伦，
do you think you'll be able to go
through with it this time?
你觉得
这次你能熬过去吗？
Tris!
三！
What, I'm only saying what we're
all thinking.
什么，我只是说我们都在
想什么。
Ow!
哦！
Subtitles by Red Bee Media
Red Bee Media 字幕